lyricsbox.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy

I got it!We use cookies to customize content and advertising, to provide social media features, and to analyze traffic to our site. We also share information about your use of our site with our trusted social media, advertising and analytics partners. [Read more](https://www.lyricsbox.com/privacy_policy.html).

Privacy has become a major concern on the Internet. Just like almost any other website, we collect personal data to provide better services to you. We know that you care how personal data is used and shared. Therefore we are committed to protecting your privacy. To this end, we have designed this privacy policy in a format that is easy to read so that you can clearly understand which personal data we collect, process, use and how we protect it, as well as how you can update, manage and delete your personal data. 

When we refer to ourselves as "we", we mean LyricsBox. LyricsBox is a company in the Netherlands. We may update this privacy policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new privacy policy on this page. You are advised to review this privacy policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this privacy policy are effective when they are posted on this page. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us using the information set forth in the contact page. 

This privacy policy is provided pursuant to the UE Regulation on data protection (General Data Protection Regulation, hereinafter "GDPR"). By using our website, you accept the practices described in this privacy policy. If you do not accept the provisions set forth herein, we invite you not to use our website. 

## Personal data collection, use and sharing

What personal data we collect depends on how you use our website. We collect personal data (i) automatically when you use our website and (ii) when you choose to voluntarily share it with us by making use of optional additional features. 

Personal data that we collect automatically 

We collect information each time you access our website. This information is data that we receive from your browser or device. Browsers and devices automatically send information to websites to identify themselves. We automatically collect personal data for log file-, analytics- and advertising purposes. 

LOG FILE INFORMATION 

Log file information that we collect includes non-personal data such as your web request, referring URL, time of your web request and other such information. Log file information also includes your IP address which is considered personal data. To collect and manage log file information we make use of cookies. See our cookie policy for more information about the cookie technology. We collect log file information for the following purposes: 

  * Operate, maintain and provide our features and services on the website
  * Personalize content and communications based on your preferences
  * Diagnose or fix technology problems
  * Improve and enhance our website
  * Prevent spam or fraudulent or abusive activity on the website
  * Meet contract or legal obligations

ANALYTICS INFORMATION 

We use Google Analytics to assist us in analyzing activity on our website. Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. The tracking operation retrieves data about the page request: time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page, referring site details (such as the URI a user came through to arrive at this site), type of web browser, type of operating system (OS), flash version, javascript support, screen resolution, screen color processing ability, network location and IP address. From all these tracked details IP address is considered personal data. Google doesn't report actual IP addresses though, IPs are used to compose geographicals reports. Google Analytics processes all data in an aggregated and anonymous form that does not identify you directly as an individual. We collect analytics information for the following purposes: 

  * Monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage, and demographic patterns on our website
  * Operate, maintain and provide our features and services on the website
  * Diagnose or fix technology problems
  * Improve and enhance our website
  * Prevent spam or fraudulent or abusive activity on the website

ADVERTISING INFORMATION 

Advertising revenue allows us to offer you our content for free and to keep improving our website. We work with third party advertising and technology companies who serve ads on our behalf. We share your IP address, which is considered personal data, with these advertisers. These advertisers may also use tracking tools such as cookies, pixel tags, and web beacons, to collect information about a user's online activities (over time and across non-affiliated websites and applications). We never share your personal data with non-affiliated third parties for their own advertising or marketing use. Click here for a list of the advertisers we work with. We adhere to self-regulatory principles for online behavioral advertising issued by the [Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA)](https://digitaladvertisingalliance.org/principles) and the [European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA)](https://www.edaa.eu/european-principles/), collectively, the OBA Principles. We use the data collected for advertising for the following purposes: 

  * Serve relevant (personalized) ads
  * Prevent you from seeing repeated ads

Personal data that you choose to share with us 

We collect personal data you voluntarily choose to share with us. We ask for this information when you would like to use additional features of our site. We keep all personal data you provide to us strictly confidential and do not sell, share, transfer or distribute it to any third party. That does not relieve you of the responsibilities associated with an improper use of our website. You are responsible for the data you provide through our website and therefore we ask you to pay attention to what you make public. 

REGISTRATION INFORMATION 

You do not need to create an account in order to access information on our website. Registration is voluntarily and only required for the following purposes: 

  * To submit a comment
  * To review content
  * To earn points for contributions
  * To browse through the website without advertising
  * To create your own playlist
  * To customize your browsing experience (such as changing the LyricsBox time to your local time or how you would style the search results)
  * To submit and edit content

If you decide to create a LyricsBox account and join our community you will have to provide a username, email address and the password you intend to use. Your email address is considered personal data and we only use it to communicate with you (for example to send you your password). Your email address is never displayed on our website. Your username is visible on our website. If you choose a username that includes or reveals your name or any other personal information, such information is public. We use registration information to: 

  * Create and manage user accounts
  * Verify the identity of users
  * Send communications
  * Provide support and assistance for the website
  * Personalize content and communications based on your preferences
  * Remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit our website
  * Customize your user experience

PROFILE INFORMATION 

If you are a registered member of our website, you have the option to add additional information on your profile. This information is name, gender and location and helps you connect with other members on our site. Name, gender and location are considered personal data. Entering this additional information is completely voluntarily. If you decided to enter it, you can control who to share this additional information with. By default, your additional information is shown to nobody. See "privacy level" in the section Your rights and options how to change visibility. We use this additional profile information to: 

  * Help you connect with other members of our site

CONTACT INFORMATION 

When you contact us through our contact page, we ask you for your name and email address. These details are considered personal data. We use this contact information to: 

  * Communicate with you

SOCIAL MEDIA INFORMATION 

If you choose to connect your social media account(s), such as Facebook, to your user profile on our website, we receive the following information from the social network: email address, name, gender and location. This information is considered personal data. The email address is used to send you your password. Name, gender and location are used as additional information on your profile. You can control who to share this additional information with. By default, your additional information is shown to nobody. See "privacy level" in the section Your rights and options how to change visibility. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third party websites and services before linking or connecting them to our website. The data we receive is dependent upon your privacy settings with the social network. We use information received from social media networks to: 

  * Create and manage user accounts
  * Verify the identity of users
  * Personalize content and communications based on your preferences
  * Remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit our website
  * Customize your user experience

## Cookies and other similar data collection technologies

We may use cookies and similar tracking technologies (like beacons, tags and scripts) for a variety of purposes. Because these tracking technologies are able to uniquely identify your browser (not you as person), they are considered personal data. For more information on how we use cookies and on your settings, please refer to our Cookie Policy. We use tracking technologies to: 

  * provide us with information about how you interact with our website
  * assist us in our marketing efforts

## Who we share your personal data with

We share personal data with others in an aggregated and anonymous form that does not identify you directly as an individual in the following ways: 

Our visitors 

Our website allows you to connect with others and share information about yourself with other individuals. Your profile information, including your username, avatar, and personal narrative, and comments you make on our website, will be available publicly to others by. Similarly, your username and avatar will be displayed alongside any comments you make on our website and will be displayed on our website on our top contributors list, or in connection with your contributions. By using our website, you acknowledge that you understand and agree that your profile information will be displayed publicly. See "privacy level" in the section Your rights and options how to change visibility. 

Third parties 

The third parties we might share your personal data with are: 

  * Ad networks and exchanges
  * Analytics service providers
  * We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this privacy policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganisation of our business.

Search engines 

Website crawlers like Google automatically crawl (i.e. make a copy for they search engine) the (public) content of our website. Any personal data publicly available could be crawled and could appear in the search results of the website crawler. They can display your information publicly. 

## Children's privacy

We considers a child to be anyone under the age of 13 (or 16 due to requirements of the GDPR if you are located in the European Union). We do not knowingly collect personal data from children. If you are a parent or guardian and believe your child has provided us with personal data without consent, please contact us and we will take steps to immediately delete its personal data. 

## How we protect your personal data

We are committed securing your personal data and have taken steps in this regard. We have put in place appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures to safeguard and secure your personal data in order to prevent unauthorized accesses, distribution, changes or elimination of your personal data. We also make use of privacy-enhancing technologies such as hashing and pseudonymization of data prior to storage, encryption of the transmission of that data or using SSL connections (Secure Socket Layer) technology. 

Remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, so we cannot guarantee its absolute security. You should take care in deciding what information you send us in this way. In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations. 

## How long do we keep your personal data

The length of time personal data is retained and criteria for determining that time are dependent on the nature of the personal data and the purpose for which it was provided. We will retain your personal data (such as your email address) as long as your account is active. We will retain your personal data (such as your IP address) as is needed to provide you our services or as is necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. Personal data used for purposes other than for your account is typically maintained only for a short period. Some backups of the data may remain in our archive servers for a reasonable period of time due to technical reasons. 

At any time you can remove your personal data or instruct us to remove it. See Your rights and options below for more information on how you can update or remove your personal data. You should be aware that we may retain certain personal data after your account has been terminated in an aggregated, anonymized form that does not longer identify you directly as an individual. We aware that after you delete your account, your comments may remain visible. We reserve the right to use your comments after you delete your account, but we ensure you that your comments are aggregated, anonymized form that does not longer identify you directly as an individual. 

## International transfer of personal data

We are headquartered in the Netherlands in the European Union (the "EU"). Your personal data may be transferred to and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. If you are located outside Netherlands and choose to provide personal data to us, please note that we transfer the data to our servers in the Netherlands and process it there. Personal data may also be transferred to, or controlled and processed by companies in other countries that help us provide our website. In some instances, these may be countries outside of the EU, where the level of protection provided by the laws of these countries may be different than the high standard enshrined in the GDPR. We will protect the privacy and security of personal data we collect in accordance with this privacy policy, regardless of where it is processed, controlled or stored. If you are accessing or using our website or otherwise providing personal data to us, you are agreeing to the transfer of your personal data. 

## Your rights and options

You have the following data protection rights and options: 

Privacy level 

If you create a LyricsBox account you'll get a profile page. This page is public. On your profile page you can optionally add additional information: age, gender and location. With the "privacy level" setting you can control to who this additional information is visible: to nobody, to your friends, to LyricsBox members or to everybody. By default your additional information is visible to nobody. You can find the privacy settings by logging in and going to the Personal Information edit form. 

Account cancellation 

You have the right to access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information. You can do this by loggin in to your account. Use the Personal Information edit form to change any additional data and/or change visibility using the privacy settings. Use the "close account" form to request deletion of your account. You can also contact us with any of these requests. In addition, if you are subject to European Data Protection Regulation, you can object to the processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us. Following the provisions of GDPR we might also require you to prove your identity (for example, by requesting an ID or other proof) in order for you to invoke the mentioned rights. This is made to ensure that no right of third parties are violated by your request, and the mentioned rights are exercised by an actual personal data subject or an authorized person. 

Opt-out from receiving emails 

You have the right to opt-out of account notification emails at any time. You can opt out in your account settings or by contacting us. If you choose to no longer receive account notifications, we may still communicate with you regarding such things as your security product functionality, responses to service requests, or any other non-marketing/administrative related purposes. 

Withdraw consent 

Similarly, if we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. 

Right to complain 

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority if you believe that our collection and use of your data is carried out in breach of the applicable law. 

Opt-out Google Analytics 

You can opt-out of having made your activity on our website available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the [Google Privacy & Terms website](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

Opt-out of certain Behavioral Advertising activities 

You can opt-out of certain Behavioral Advertising activities by doing one or more of the following. Please note that you will need to opt-out of each browser and device for which you desire to apply these opt-out features. 

  * Service Provider Opt Out  
You can opt-out directly from some Advertising Service Providers and providers of Tracking Tools by using their opt-out tools. Some of these service providers, and links to their opt-out tools, are: Google Analytics: with a privacy policy at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ and opt out at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
  * Industry Opt Out Tools  
Some Advertising Service Providers or providers of Tracking Tools may participate in the Network Advertising Initiative's (NAI) Opt-Out Tool (http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) Consumer Choice Page (http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), and you can opt-out of certain services and learn more about your choices by visiting the links included here. Users in the EU can visit http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ for more information about your choices and to opt out of participating service providers.
  * Web Browser Controls  
You can prevent the use of certain Tracking Tools, such as cookies, on a device-by-device basis using the controls in your web browser. These controls can be found in the Tools > Internet Options (or similar) menu for your browser, or as otherwise directed by your browser's support feature. Through your web browser, you may be able to: Delete existing Tracking Tools, Disable future Tracking Tools, Set your browser to provide you with a warning each time a cookie or certain other Tracking Tools are being set
  * Mobile Opt Out  
Your mobile devices may offer settings that enable you to make choices about the collection, use, or transfer of mobile app information for Behavioral Advertising. You may also opt-out of certain Tracking Tools on mobile devices by installing the DAA's AppChoice app on your mobile device (for iTunes, visit https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/appchoices/id894822870?mt=8, for Android, visit https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.DAA.appchoices&hl=en). For more information, please visit http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4228, https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en or http://www.applicationprivacy.org/expressing-your-behavioral-advertising-choices-on-a-mobile-device, as applicable.
  * Do Not Track  
Your browser may offer you a "Do Not Track" option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. The Service does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we collect information about your online activity both while you are using the Service and after you leave our Service. We collect certain persistent identifiers from your browser or mobile device to assist us with providing and improving the Service. Because we collect browsing and persistent identifier data (only for analytic and internal purposes), your selection of the "Do Not Track" option provided by your mobile browser will not have any effect on our collection of analytics information or the collection of a persistent identifier.
